Holy smokes, there's a lot to talk about
regarding the SpaceX situation,
including the lockups that might not
actually be lockup expired. We'll talk
about that. The technical rebound we're
getting on SpaceX stock. We'll talk
about that. We're also going to talk, of
course, about the Terra Fab. In fact,
that's where we're going to start. And
then we're going to end by talking about
iron and this the other neocloud data
center plays revenues. And we're going
to focus on facts because as usual there
are some knuckleheads on the internet
that like being really loud. I don't
like cabbage tigers
and and then you know we forget that
there's a 30 minute video often of
facts. And uh that's what we're going to
do is we're going to focus on facts, not
a oneline sentence. We're going to focus
on what I think 99% of reasonable Tesla,
SpaceX, and Elon investors care about,
myself included, given that I started
sharing Tesla facts back in 2017 when I
bought my first Tesla, and I've been a
fan. Of course, uh the uh the I'm not so
kneede that I can't criticize. That has
led to some entertaining outcomes.
Although I have been at the Tesla
shareholder meetings, convinced Elon to
advertise Tesla features and ended up
after that using AI to make Ryan
Reynolds pitch Teslas, which went
insanely viral, leading to a duel
between Ryan Reynolds Aviation Jin, who
responded to my AI video of uh of him
pitching Teslas, and they responded with
an AI generation of Elon pitching
aviation jin. [laughter]
That was epic until of course I got a
very strongly worded letter demanding I
delete my post which I subsequently did.
Anyway, so where were we? Let's get
started. The terrafab ah fell energy
free electron laser lithography. Uh, in
case you're not familiar, FEL, by the
way, which is the acronym that Elon used
to sort of confirm this Easter egg in
this video, is um
something that Tolken brought up from
the Lord of the Rings series, right? The
author. Uh, it's also from World of
Warcraft. It also happens there happens
to be some te some fell energy behind me
as well. [laughter] But, um, free
electron laser lithography is really
cool. It's conceptual. It's academic.
And I'm going to show you where it comes
from. Basically, here you have this
futuristic version of the Terapab,
obviously CGI. We've got uh Robo Vans,
you know, maybe a Whoa, maybe Grock AI
put it together. This is all really
cool. This multi-levelled highway, you
know, everybody's always wanted this. We
like trees. You know, this is cool. Uh
building vertically. We thought the
future would have more of this. This is
really selling us the future. We haven't
seen a lot of it yet. Here's obviously a
giant Starship space terap, but there's
an Easter egg in here. And the Easter
egg has to do with this circle around
the outside which Elon has since
confirmed.
This is essentially a particle reactor
uh light. It gets magnified as a laser
uh in a tunnel electrified highly bright
laser. And you use this to essentially
etch wafers beyond ASML's current
capabilities and to a level that has
never been done before. If Elon can pull
this off, it would represent a
multi-deade
leap forward in manufacturing chips.
Obviously,
we have had summaries like that before
in regards to things like the 4680.
We're going to hire the best people.
We've got the most ambitious battery
technology ever. Uh, it's going to be a
structural battery. It's going to make
the car safer. The output's going to be
higher. The costs are going to be lower.
Boom. What ends up happening? We get
delayed. We have nominal yields and
reality is just never as fun as the
expectations. Uh and so we have to be a
little cautious.
SpaceX and Elon have zero experience
operating a fab. They have a test or
research facility going on over at Giga
Texas. Uh this is the research uh
facility that they're they're trying to
start spitting out wafers with, which is
cool. This is great. Uh and and this is
all very aspirational. Tesla operates
the research fab at Giga Austin and this
facility which is planned is coming to
Grimes County, Texas, 100 million square
feet. Expected investment somewhere
between 55 billion to 119 billion. But
just know that ring you see around the
outside should be thought of as a call
option. In fact, honestly, a lot of this
facility should be thought of as a call
option. Uh the projected time frame is
they'll actually have test patches in
2027 ramping in the second half of 2027.
Um great. I call this a 2030 call
option, especially since data centers
aren't the easiest to get up and
running. For example, let me just give
you a quick timeline expectation here.
Governor Abbott of Texas has recently
directed an audit of every single data
center progressing in Texas. no
approvals until audits are complete
based on power and water concerns. Now,
SpaceX lead development on this
facility, Riley Treddle, has suggested
that we're going to build a massive
natural gas uh power plant. In fact,
multiple of them. We're going to build
large battery arrays in order to store
this energy off-rid.
That's great. If you could do this
off-rid, you can bypass some of those
Greg Abbott audits, but you still need
permits for those natural gas turbine
plants. in those natural gas turbine
plants like an actual natural gas
facility unless you're using something
like a Bloom Energy which could be done
very quickly. You know, Bloom Energy,
you know, those things could be popped
up in like 3 to four months. If you're
actually going to build a real natural
gas peaker plant, you know, you're
probably looking at a 3 to four year
time frame just to get the power that
you need. That's obviously a downside
risk and and that's why I think 2030 is
a realistic call option for this
Terraab. uh you know in spite of how uh
sexy and desirable and exciting this
this is there there is real risk for
delay here. Keep in mind this is very
different from micro and macro hard.
Micro and macro hard are not for orbital
um compute whereas Terapab is actually
expected 80%wise to be used for
uh data centers in space orbital chips
that will be used uh in satellites 20%
potentially for full self-driving and
Optimus robots that's where the Tesla
partnership comes in but uh this is uh
you know those would be like the AI6
chips whereas the orbital chips
considered to be called the D3 chips.
Cool ideas. Hopefully, we can get there.
But what's a lot more near-term and more
important to our conversation, I think,
is actually what's going on with the
lockup stock and micro macro hard. So,
micro macro hard are uh on Earth
facilities. These are compute for Earth.
They'll likely be mostly GB300's,
Reuben's, and the next generations.
They're expected between 2027 and 2028.
That's great. That's the on earth buying
more Nvidia chips, which Elon confirmed
they're going to buy more Nvidia chips.
It's actually great for Nvidia stock.
Uh, and Nvidia stock has reacted up and
AMD stock has reacted down on this. Uh,
Nvidia is near its all-time highs at the
moment. A lot of stocks moving today.
We've got obviously SpaceX moving as
well, which we'll talk about. But, you
know, Nvidia is still, if you if you can
actually assume that their growth rate
is going to stay relatively high, then
they look relatively cheap. Assuming
that growth, I still maintain they could
get to $300. It's not my favorite
investment to make because I think we
have maybe one more hardware cycle, like
one more good boom in hardware from
hardware stocks, and then we're kind of
getting to the end of the hardware
cycle. I'm still bearish on on the
memory plays themselves. mostly because
uh we we expect memory will be extremely
cyclical and we've got a lot of supply
coming on but that's I'll film a
different video. What's more interesting
here is not just the potential win here
on Nvidia. Uh but also what's going on
with SpaceX stock the lockups and then
what we're thinking about compute
especially from macro micro hard and uh
leasing rates. So we got to talk about
that. So let's talk about this lockup.
First things first, we're getting to
where we could actually uh start drawing
in retracement lines. Here we can see
we've got our first retracement test
would actually be at $133.34.
Taking the top to the bottom here, uh we
expected on Thursday the lockup of
SpaceX to go from 4.9% to 11.8%.
And a lot of people asked me, Kevin, in
in fact, we had our conversation about
this uh yesterday morning in the course
member liveream. A lot of people said,
"Hey, Kevin, you know, lockup's coming.
Are we expecting a big dump on Tesla
stock?" And yesterday morning in the
course of my live stream, I said, "No,
that lockup news is already going to be
priced in likely. In fact, it'll likely
go green. And it's not as easy to sell
as people think." Boom. What do we have?
Stock bottom hits yesterday because
people think a massive amount of selling
pressure is going to come on Thursday.
It doesn't. Stock ends up up 6% on buy
the dip buying. People think the bottom
is in. And if that's the first lock up
and no damage is done, the bottom is in.
That stock's up another, you know, 11
whatever percent today. This is in
fairness what we said in our course of
the live stream, which remember you can
always join that. You get lifetime
access over here. Join us before we have
our big price increases in August. Two
massive bacon price uh two massive and
large price increases coming. Uh
remember, you could likely write this
membership off on your taxes and you get
to be part of those course member live
streams. You get all the trade alerts,
the courses, the alpha reports we do
every morning. Uh most tax professionals
say you could write this off. You get
access to uh what we're doing over here
as listed at mekevin.com. So come there,
join and check it out. But let's talk
about this. So why is this factually
happening? Why did the lockups not hit?
Well, a lot has to do with the serious
multi-step operational bottlenecks to
selling. For example, I got an email on
our SpaceX exposure, which we have a lot
of SpaceX exposure that we got, you
know, back when this was like a $300
billion company. And uh the email that I
got indicates that they've basically got
to get the restriction stamp removed
from the share certificates on the cap
table and with the transfer agent. Once
that gets removed, which the process for
that was able to start yesterday. Once
that gets removed, then shares can get
delivered to fund managers and then from
fund managers, they could get delivered
to actual brokerage accounts at
investors. So for example, my venture
capital fund is an investor. It's it's
not a fund uh in the sense that it's a
fund manager managing individual
people's allocation. It's it's a venture
capital fund, right? And so it has its
own essentially brokerage account. Uh
and so what happens is once a transfer
agent goes from removing stamps on those
shares which legally could start
happening yesterday then it gets sent to
a fund manager which then could get
distributed to essentially the end
investors who could then eventually
sell. We have no idea when that is going
to be and that's only going to be part
of right because obviously the lockups
are coming. This is only going from 4.9
to 11. We're expecting to get to like
50% free float here. So basically 10x
where we were before uh when this IPOed.
In addition to that, uh some other
shares, especially from the XAI merger,
we'll actually have to wait until
February second because of the 12-month
holding period from the 144 rule. So
practically
and bottom line here, I think a lot of
people think that this lockup came and
went without a hitch. Wow, all that was
absorbed. But the lock up selling
pressure really hasn't actually started
yet. And that's normal because it takes
time to do it. And in fairness, markets
did price a lot of this in already. So
the question now is, can the buy the
dipping we're seeing on SpaceX offset
the true selling pressure hasn't
actually started yet to be determined.
So expect more volatility. Basically,
you could use technical analysis to help
you mostly because I think what'll
happen is uh people will use TA to help
time exits, you know, as as they get to,
you know, various different rejection
levels and who knows if we'll actually
uh extend up. Frankly, you know,
something you could do as well is you
could set you could draw your extension
down um uh by drawing up from the bottom
rather uh rather than an extension up.
And so if we do that, let's see here.
Let's go draw our top at 64, 103. It's
slightly different lines here and here,
which is totally expected, but um yeah,
we're not going to extend down to 30, I
don't think. So, I don't know that that
line's as useful. We'll get rid of this
fib uh retracement set right here. And
there we go. We'll stick with this.
We'll stick with the extension mostly
because I think if this puppy falls to
80 bucks, 80 60 to 80 bucks I think is
a,
you know, a nicer place to buy this. I'm
not saying don't buy it in the low 100s,
but I think that's a nicer place to buy
it. I think a lot of people will buy it
by then. Uh anyway, so
what do we have for the uh cloud
situation? All right, so this is where
things actually get interesting with
fact as well. And we got to talk about
this because a lot of the cloud demand
that we're seeing for SpaceX uh Colossus
1 and 2 from XAI uh is is reasonable.
We're seeing massive demand acceleration
because of Codex and Fable. Q1 really
led to an inflection point in annual
recurring revenue for these companies.
Anthropics ARR is up like 50x today. You
know, 50 billion ARR and GPU rental
pricing has also shot up. This is
actually good for SpaceX. So if you look
at GPU spot in rental pricing, you can
see we had this sort of flatlining over
here in 2025. We've actually really
inflected up in Q1. And the hope is that
this is going to continue, especially on
these GB300 chips, which are obviously
the most recent vintage and so they have
the they command the highest premium.
You can see the uh A100's over here
still generating money, which is great
because, you know, they're like an
8-year-old chip, which is good. But data
centers, you know, they've got a long
lead time for the stuff to come online.
And so it's natural for these to hold
pricing power for a while until we
actually build out this compute people
are expecting to come online, including
Terraab. So this big debate that's going
on right now, or I should say a big
debate that's going on right now, is is
Elon's uh projected rental rate
reasonable for uh SpaceX? And Elon is
projecting 30 to40 billion per gawatt or
30 to40 million per megawatt. You know,
it doesn't really matter. Just 30 to 40
is what you got to think about uh per
year. And uh some people are saying that
is 3 to 4x industry average and it's
true. It is. Other people uh for example
this one person on X that I actually
respect who doesn't have emotional
commentary because some people get
really emotional uh about this kind of
stuff. this person in Southern Value,
he's like, "Oh, you know, if the AI labs
pay Elon's rates of 30 to40 billion
dollars, they're not going to have any
money left. They're not going to be able
to pay these rates. There won't be any
money left because that's basically all
their money. So, it's not good." Another
thing that's not good is using a wet
wipe when you're trying to get a dry
board. They do call them dry erase
markers. I don't know if that's why they
call them dry erase because you gota
they only write when they're dry or it's
because they erase dry. That's probably
more likely what it is. [laughter] But
anyway, so uh the point is uh this this
forecast from Elon of 30 to40 billion is
really exciting and it's leading a lot
of people to speculate that they're
going to be able to um really create a
profitable business on the AI vertical.
The big question or problem that we run
into is this. the SpaceX contracts that
we find for some reason are just much
more expensive than the rest of the
industry. Uh and that is the question.
Why is there such a gap? And so one
possible explanation is availability, a
premium because Google and Anthropic
want this availability and so they're
willing to pay higher GPU per hour
rates. Uh and
potentially all in a similar cluster and
maybe that could be true for micro
macroart as well. The big problem that
we see is not that oh Elon was able to
get the premium now that's not the issue
few things to break down and then we
could really see the issue right so
first we have uh the revenue premium
okay Elon at 30 to 40 and we have the
cost we'll talk about the cost in just a
moment so first regarding that revenue
premium of 30 to 40. Let's understand
when the market right now is sitting
between 10 and 15 million uh per
megawatt. Elon's sitting easily in his
projections uh and his recent anthropic
and Google rates at 3 to 5x what the
market is able to substantiate or or or
prove. The only benchmark is Elon's deal
with Google Anthropic. And both of them
have reasons to see SpaceX stock do
well. Mostly which we talked about in
our last video, which is Google's $94
billion exposure to SpaceX stock, which
could lead to some preferential
treatment. And then also Google's
investments in Anthropic. It's a little
bit circular. The guaranteeing of some
of these data centers. There's a lot
here which then props up Anthropic,
which you know is a customer of SpaceX,
which helps Google. It's a big circle.
We already know that. But the bigger
issue is companies like uh Enbis, Iron,
Cororeweave, these guys are renting out
compute for 9 to15 million per megawatt.
We'll go with million per megawatt.
Again, you could do billion per gawatt.
It doesn't matter. It's the same ratio.
And that's where the concern is. Why is
the spread so large? Uh the thing that
people will say is, oh well, Elon gets a
premium because he has the availability.
But then they also forget to mention the
90-day cancellation contract, which
we've talked about before. We already
know based on my last video that there
are massive cancellation rights uh that
these uh uh rental contracts come with,
which isn't great. Now, regarding the uh
$2.7
million per megawatt argument, this was
in an IPO draft from Tesla, which they
then deleted, but Medium picked up and
started pitching. Remember this has to
do with brownfield. No GPUs, no servers.
We already know that. That's old news.
We already talked about the um how
should we say the uh the consequences of
of this being unrealistic. We're not
worried about the cost to build being
unrealistic. We know the GPUs are
expensive. We already know that. The big
debate right now in in the financial
community is is Elon earning this
premium sustainable? And a lot of people
would say no. mostly because in order to
argue that SpaceX's ben like somehow
sets the benchmark if that's the case
and SpaceX's benchmark is going to be
the new market rate if this is going to
be the new market rate probably
anthropic and open AAI won't be anywhere
near profitability which means they
won't be able to support paying these
numbers anymore I mean we know they're
not near actual profitability now but
I'm just saying the hope of that goes
away that's a risk factor is that people
can't actually even consistently pay
those rates They could pay a little bit
of those rates but not all those rates.
That's the big question. But even if
let's say they could sustain these, who
is that actually better for? If this is
the new market rate for compute and
that's already being priced in for
SpaceX, wouldn't it then be true that
iron and corewave
would have to adjust up which would
actually make the Neoclouds a
potentially better investment than
SpaceX because SpaceX is already pricing
in their pricing if they're the
benchmark and these guys would get to
catch up on renewal terms which that's
the big risk with SpaceX. X compute is
renewal is are these going to renew and
second half of that are new contracts
actually going to be able to come in at
that benchmark. So if we can't renew the
anthropic and Google contracts at these
levels
then the projections are all off by a
multiple.
If new contracts don't come in at this
level this is really misleading anyway.
it's fugazi and we won't know that until
we actually see what happens with
compute over the next year or two. But
those are the real risks and I think
markets are getting a little ahead of
pricing in that oh that new benchmark is
definitely the standard because keep in
mind you do have more buildouts coming
and it's not just from the Neoclouds is
even meta. I mean Meta is looking to
sell one to two gawatts worth of compute
between 27 and 28. A lot of this, by the
way, they're renting out the Google uh
TPUs and they're using their own
in-house TPUs. So, we'll see. Point is,
you know, we're still in the deciding
phase. It's too early to say with
certainty that there is no risk,
especially with 90-day consolation uh
cancellation terms, that there is no
risk to SpaceX pricing when you know
what's being paid for their GPU hours
for basically the same damn chip. It
doesn't make sense. And I think that's
the the point here to make is here.
Let's draw let's make this a little bit
more obvious. Let's put like a giant
arrow here. Okay, see this GB300
between a deal with IED and Microsoft or
Nvidia and Sharon AI. These GPUs are
being rented at under $3 per hour.
And these GPU rental rates have gone up.
Look, in May the Iron and Nvidia rental
rates are $4. But somehow SpaceX's GB300
rental rate is at $11
and the mixed blended rate of H100 H200
which went rent went rent went rent went
rent went rent went rent went rent went
rent went for way less than some 200s is
somehow $5. So somehow there is this
massive spread and nobody really has a
good explanation for that other than
saying well it's the Elon premium or
it's the availability premium. Well,
there was clearly availability at these
companies at IR and their capacity is
expanding. It's except they they weren't
able to command that sort of premium. So
why seems weird. We already expect Corey
to grow revenue by 33 to $33 billion
from $13 billion. They're expanding and
business is expected to go from $551
billion in ARR to 7 to9 billion in ARR
by the end of 2026.
INEN themselves thinks they're going to
see ARR of four billion by the end of
2026. And of course you've got uh you
know Microsoft, Amazon and Google also
pushing for their own data centers with
Meta as well. We know that Meta mostly
with their offbalance sheet uh leasing
agreements which also have cancellation
terms in them. Point is, this is all
obviously circular, but for some reason,
and this was the point of the last
video, Elon gets fat premiums. And the
movement of SpaceX stock in the short
term or, you know, somebody trying to be
mean on social media and go, "But you're
titled C, your title this that or
whatever doesn't remove the problem. We
don't know what the renewal rates are
going to be. We don't know what the new
contracts are going to price at that
don't have a circular relation to
SpaceX, that don't have a vested
interest in SpaceX stock and a technical
bounce following a lock lock up that
hasn't actually occurred yet
practically, right? like legally it has
practically it hasn't is cool but it
doesn't mean oh the bottom's definitely
in uh the compute prices are guaranteed
and I'm not bearish on space I hope it
goes up the more I I just want to make
this clear I think people forget this
more SpaceX goes up the more money I
make okay it's that simple SpaceX go up
daddy make more money
really happy I saw coffee left. Okay.
Like, let's be clear about the bias. I
would love for it to go up, but then
Kevin, why are you making a video,
you know, putting out these risk
factors? Because that's what I do. I
cover risk factors and what happens in
the financial community. If there are
risks you should be aware of, then
they're good for you to know because
maybe they'll take somebody listening to
this. All right, maybe I won't go all in
on margin on SpaceX because there are
still risks.
Good,
right? That's the whole point. I'm not
here to give you personalized advice
about exactly what you should do with
your money because I don't know your
situation. But I think you should be
aware of these things so that way when
when people blindly say, "Oh my gosh,
iron and core, they're definitely going
to go to the benchmark of SpaceX rates."
H the rates that were set by companies
who were incentivized to see SpaceX
stock go up. Not the best thesis. Okay,
just saying. Like when you have the
extra insight go, damn it, Kevin. This
is why even though I hate you, I still
have to watch you. Bye. Thanks for
watching, folks. We'll see you in the
next one. Goodbye. Good luck. And join
us over at me.com. You can talk to me
directly in the course of live streams.
[music] You get the alpha award every
day. Goodbye and see you soon.
>> Why not advertise these things that you
told us here? I feel like nobody else
knows about this.
>> We'll we'll try a little advertising and
see how it goes.
>> Congratulations, man. [music] You have
done so much. People love you. People
look up to you.
>> Kevin Praat there, financial analyst and
YouTuber. Meet Kevin. Always great to
get your take.